Thomas Dodson

14 Salisbury Grove, Armley, Leeds, LS12 2AS.
07703789861 • tw.dodson@yahoo.co.uk
Linkedin Profile • www.linkedin.com/in/thomas-dodson-2409441a
Website • https://twdstudent.github.io/thomas-dodson-resume/

Personal statement

I recently achieved a diploma in software development through the Code Institute whilst working full time as an Assistant Manager. I decided to enrol myself onto the "Full Stack Web Developer" course to help with my career change. The reason I did this was to help me pursue my interest in web design and web development along with marrying my newly acquired skill set with my other passion of photography.

I would now like to utilise the skills and experience gained from my years in retail management and undertake a new challenge in the world of web design and development.

Key Skills

- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and Python coding languages.
- Familiar with developer's frame works such as Bootstrap, jQuery, Flask and Django.
- Excellent management and team development skills.
- Extensive experience in managing 6-figure yearly employment budget.
- Strong P&L management skills allowing the business to maximise profits.
- · Advanced in developing and executing business plans.
- Photography.

Employment History

Assistant Manager-Scarbrough Hotel.

(January 2007 - Present)

I have a key role in delivering:

- Guests-Brand leading (80 businesses) guest satisfaction scores.
- Profit-£1.5 million turnover, constant sales growth and excellent profit conversion.
- Practices-Company Leading (1700+ businesses) food and fire safety scores.
- People-consistently below brand and industry staff turnover figures.

Photographer-Rayner Photography.

(2012-2014)

Achievements and responsibilities:

- Co-ordinating photo shoots for large sporting events nationwide.
- Award ceremonies were handled with discretion and professionalism.

- Production of photographic material to high standard under tight deadlines.
- · Sales of final product, satisfying both the client and management.

Photographer-Free Lance.

Achievements and responsibilities:

- Kept to client brief and ensured tight deadlines were met.
- · Liaised with PR agencies to meet client briefs.
- Provided photographic material for marketing and publications.
- Had images published in the Yorkshire Evening Post and The Guardian.
- Created photographic material for the new websites.
- · Co-ordinated food photography for the new menus.
- · Provided photography for private re-launch nights.

Education

Code Institute.

(Graduated January 31st, 2020)

Diploma in software development.

West Leeds High School (Sixth Form).

(September 2004 – June 2006)

A-levels:

- Photography A
- English Literature C
- Biology C

West Leeds High School.

(September 1999 – June 2004)

10 GCSEs, grade A-C, including Maths and English

Other Qualifications

- National Certificate of Personal License Holder (NCPLH).
- First Aid Certificate, level 2.
- · Cask Master Certificate.